Daniel Wamuya

Frontend Developer

Phone: (254) 0798 164 378 | Email: dwamuya@gmail.com | Website: dwamuya.me Github: github.com/dannywamuya | Address: Nairobi, Kenya

Summary

A well-qualified Software Engineer with 3 years of work experience designing, building and scaling web applications. Proficient and collaborative team player with excellent communication skills and technical skills in web development.

Skills

React, Typescript, Javascript(ES6), HTML5, CSS3, gRPC, Nodejs, Nextjs, Firebase, Figma, Git, Github, PostgreSql

Work Experience

Leta Technologies

Software Engineer - Nairobi, Kenya

Feb 2022 to September 2022

- Implemented a monorepo architecture for code reuse between multiple frontend applications.
- Integrated the backend with the frontend, which included migrating the communication from HTTP to gRPC. This required a strong understanding of modern frontend technologies and experience with gRPC.
- Designed and implemented the user interface ensuring that the dashboard was performant and user-friendly.
- Collaborated with the backend team to ensure seamless integration between the frontend and backend.

Afrex Gold Limited

Full Stack Developer - Thika, Kenya

Feb 2021 to August 2021

- Designed and developed an optimized website with Angular and Nodejs to support digital marketing.
- Employed coding practices based on best accepted standards to establish great user interface and experience.

MyMoviesAfrica

Android Developer Intern - Nairobi, Kenya

Dec 2020 to Jan 2021

- Led highly productive scrum team of developers reviewing and testing submitted code to ensure a streamlined and bug safe development process.
- Implemented integration and unit testing to fix bugs and runtime errors in previously built and newly integrated solutions for quick bug resolution.

Education

Moringa School

Full Stack Software Development

August 2020 to Jan 2021

- Specialized in Android development with Java and Android Studio with NoSQL databases for scalable data storage on Firebase.
- Learned web development with SparkJava for RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL and Angular.